

Noah Corbett

Boca Raton, FL 561.297.3340 ncorbett2014@fau.edu

Homepage in linkedin

SUMMARY

I am a fourth year doctoral candidate in the Department of Mathematics and Statistics at Florida Atlantic University studying computational dynamical systems and differential equations. In my current research, I am developing methods that employ functional-analytic techniques and computer-assisted proofs to calculate connecting orbits in chaotic systems of ordinary differential equations and state-dependent delay differential equations, as well as travelling wave solutions of partial differential equations. In general, I view the computer as an invaluable tool in mathematics research and I enjoy learning and developing computational techniques to study open problems in mathematics.

EDUCATION _

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY. Mathematics

Fall 2024 (Expected)

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

• 3.98/4.00 GPA

MASTER OF SCIENCE, Mathematics

2020

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

- MS Presentation: The Stable Manifold Theorem
- 4.00/4.00 GPA

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, Mathematics

2018

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

- Minor in Statistics
- 3.84/4.00 GPA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT

2018-Current

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

• Duties include tutoring, grading, and teaching for undergraduate courses in mathematics and statistics

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

2020-2021, 2022-2024

FLORIDA ATLANTIC UNIVERSITY

• Partially supported to perform data analysis on an NSF-funded project in collaboration with FAU's College of Education

NSF MATHEMATICAL SCIENCES GRADUATE RESEARCH INTERN

2023

U.S. ARMY CORPS OF ENGINEERS' RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT CENTER

Intensive summer-long applied mathematics research program, funded by the NSF and administered by ORISE

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

As Course Instructor

- MAS 2103 Matrix Theory (Spring 2024)
- MAC 2312 Calculus with Analytic Geometry 2 (Fall 2023, Spring 2023)
- MAP 3305 Engineering Mathematics 1 (Fall 2022, Spring 2022)
- MAC 1105 College Algebra (Fall 2021)
- STA 2023 Introductory Statistics (Spring 2020)
- MAC 2233B Methods of Calculus (Fall 2019)

AS TEACHING ASSISTANT/EMBEDDED TUTOR

- MAS 2103 Matrix Theory (Summer 2024)
- MAD 3400 Numerical Methods (Fall 2023)
- MAD 2104 Discrete Mathematics (Summer 2022)
- STA 3100 Computational Statistics (Spring 2021)

PUBL	LICATIONS	
[1]	"Periodic orbits for state-dependent delay differential equations"	Submitted April 2024
	WITH V. NAUDOT	
[2]	"Predicting State Switches in Chaotic Dynamical Systems"	Submitted March 2024
	WITH K. PILKIEWICZ AND M. MAYO	
[3]	"Stability of Travelling Waves: A Computer-Assisted Approach"	In preparation
	WITH J. MIRELES-JAMES	
[4]	"RECRUITMENT AND RETENTION OF STEM TEACHERS IN HIGH NEED SCHOOLS:	In preparation
	AN ALUMNI SURVEY ANALYSIS OF SELECTED NSF ROBERT NOYCE PROGRAMS"	
	WITH D. KUMAR AND S. MOFFITT	
[5]	"A MIXED METHOD STUDY OF STEM TEACHER SUPPLY TO HIGH NEED SCHOOLS	In preparation
	IN FLORIDA AND TEXAS"	
	WITH D. KUMAR, S. MOFFITT, AND C. RESTREPO-WIDNEY	
Oct	rers, Presentations, & Lectures	
	RIODIC ORBITS FOR STATE-DEPENDENT DELAY DIFFERENTIAL EQUATIONS	
	APER PRESENTED AT:	4 11 24 222
• 9	2024 Florida Women in Math Day, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL. Special Session on Recent Developments in Nonlinear and Computational Dynamics, Spring 2024 AMS Eastern Sectional Meeting, Howard University, Washington, D.C.	April 21, 2024 April 7, 2024
	Graduate Student Seminar, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL.	March 29, 2024
PR	REDICTING STATE SWITCHES IN CHAOTIC DYNAMICAL SYSTEMS	
	PER PRESENTED AT:	
	13 th Annual FAU Broward Research Symposium, Florida Atlantic University, Davie, FL.	November 17, 202.
	Graduate Student Seminar, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL. Analysis & Applications Seminar, Florida Atlantic University, Boca Raton, FL.	November 2, 2023
	2023 NSF MSGI Summer Research Symposium (<i>Virtual Event</i>)	October 19, 202. August 22, 202.
	Environmental Processes Branch Seminar, USACE ERDC, Vicksburg, MS.	August 10, 2023
	ie Stable Manifold Theorem	
• [M.S. Presentation, Florida Atlantic University	April 17, 2020
Тн	IE DYNAMICS OF CIRCLE MAPS AND DENJOY'S THEOREM	
• 1	Multi-class lecture for graduate course in Dynamical Systems at Florida Atlantic University	February 2020

• Multi-class lecture for graduate course in Dynamical Systems at Florida Atlantic University

February 2020

THE FOURIER TRANSFORM, REGULARITY, AND SOBOLEV EMBEDDING

Lecture for graduate course in Partial Differential Equations at Florida Atlantic University

November 2019

PROGRAMMING EXPERIENCE _

LANGUAGES Experienced: MATLAB | R | LATEX Familiar: Python | SageMath RELEVANT SKILLS | INTLAB | RStudio | R Markdown | ggplots2 | Shiny | NumPy

FELLOWSHIPS & SCHOLARSHIPS

ISAAC SCHUR GRADUATE SCHOLARSHIP

2021

- Awarded to graduate students in mathematics who have successfully passed two qualifying exams, maintained a high GPA in graduate studies, and received distinguished letters of recommendation from two professors
- Award of \$1,000

FAU PRESIDENTIAL FELLOWSHIP

2018-2020

- Two-year fellowship awarded to doctoral students who have exhibited an excellent academic record and excellent letters of recommendation as determined by faculty at the time of admission
- Award of \$5,000 per year for the first two years of graduate studies

· Undergraduate scholarship awarded to Florida public university attendees with distinguished GPAs and SAT scores

ACTIVITIES _

GRADUATE STUDENT SEMINAR, Organizer

2022-Current

Organized and co-hosted weekly seminars, with presentations by graduate students and faculty within FAU's Department of Mathematical Sciences

AMS STUDENT CHAPTER

President

2023-Current

• Organized and lead chapter meetings, aided in organizing chapter events, and recruited officers and members for AMS student chapter.

Treasurer 2022-2023

• Managed funds and purchases for AMS-related events and activities at Florida Atlantic University

FLORIDA ATLANTIC JAZZ ORCHESTRA, Lead Trombone

2016-2017, 2024-Current

• Attended biweekly rehearsals and performed at various venues for concerts and events as the first-chair trombone player

CERTIFICATES & HONORS

- ACS Disaster Response Certificate (2024)
- CITI Responsible Conduct of Research Certificate (2023)
- CITI Social & Behavioral Research Investigators Certificate (2022)
- CRLA Level 3 Certified Tutor (2018)
- FAU Honors Program (2015-2018)